Antoine Soetewey

antoinesoetewey.com · antoine.soetewey@uclouvain.be

Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical methods applied to cancer patients.

In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level. I also provide trainings and consulting in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service.

In my spare time, I write about statistics and code in R via my blog statsandr.com.

	Education
2017 - 2024	 PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium Thesis: Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit) All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research
2015 – 2016	MSc in econometrics & operations research – Maastricht University, Netherlands - Thesis: <i>Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data</i> (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk)
2013 – 2015	 MSc in economics – KULeuven, Belgium Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen) Faculty exchange of one semester at University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA
2010 - 2013	BSc in economics & management sciences – UCLouvain, Belgium
	Teaching experience
2024	Visiting lecturer for the course "Advanced quantitative methods" – UNamur, Belgium
2017 – Present	Teaching assistant in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium - See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching
2018 – Present	Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates in statistics – SMCS, Belgium

Industry experience

2018 - Present

Consultant in statistics and data analysis for:

- Researchers and academics SMCS, Belgium
- Professionals and companies datanalyze.be

2016 - 2017

Data scientist - Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

Technical skills & languages

Software

- R (RStudio, R Markdown & Quarto, R Shiny), Jamovi, GitHub/GitLab, LATEX
- Web development
- See examples of projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (basic)